Hassan Habib Juma

Computer Scientist

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Microsoft Office, Customer Service, Strategic Planning, Teamwork, and Public Speaking. Strong engineering professional undergraduate of Daystar University.

jumahhassan67@gmail.com

0729164222

Nairobi, Kenya

Github.com/jumahhassan

Instagram.com/hassanigraphix



EDUCATION

Daystar University

08/2016 to Present Course

BSc Computer Science

High School

Ratang'a High School

01/2009 to 11/2012

Homabay County

WORK EXPERIENCE

DB Manager

Track and Trace Company, Parklands

08/2018 - 12/2018

Nairobi

Athi River

Managed fleet Database and Sorted for ease of access

Contact: Judy Njeri customercare@trackntrace.co.ke

Web Development

Freelance

01/2019 - 08/2019

Nairobi

I designed numerous websites as a freelancer for my clients using WordPress

Contact: Winnie Rotich 0719748225

Android Development

Daystar University

02/2021 - 04/2021

Athi River

This was my class project where I designed an android application to book train using XML and Kotlin

Contact: Anthony Wambua 0721589325

SKILLS

CCNA Windows Server Management HTML Java CSS
Kotlin XML Wordpress Joomla Javascript Data Analytics
Network Administration Cybersecurity MS Office

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Network Administration (08/2019 – 11/2019)

 I fixed computer server problems. I can organize, install, and support the organization's computer systems, including local area networks (LANs), wide area networks (WANs), network segments, intranets, and other data communication systems.

<u>IoE: Temperature and Humidity Sensor (02/2021 - 3/2021)</u>

 The project involved simulating and designing a temperature and humidity sensor that can be used for homes.

SolarWinds Hack (04/2021 – 06/2021)

 The project was to illustrate the relevance and context of the underlying IoC by showing how this IoC is related to the compromise.

ORGANIZATIONS

Track and Trace Company (08/2018 – 12/2018)

CERTIFICATIONS

First Aid Certificate (09/2015 – 11/2015)

In case of a life-threatening medical emergency situation, I have proper knowledge on how to handle the matter.

Languages:

English French Arabic Swahili

INTERESTS

Networking Programming Cybersecurity Graphics Design Swimming